SCOTT ISEBRAND

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

212-595-9237 | scottisebrand@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/isebrand/

Website: https://benevolent-youtiao-efa0f5.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/ScottIsebrand

A collaborative college-educated software engineer providing critical support for leadership's vision and company goals. Over 10 years of experience leading teams and creating and improving processes and standard operating procedures while assuring that customers receive sustainable and positive solutions. Possesses an analytic and organized mindset while developing strong working relationships in a team environment. Excellent verbal communication skills complemented with a great attention to detail and prioritization. Able to maintain the utmost confidentiality.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, React, SQL

Productivity Microsoft Suite (Outlook, Excel, Word, PowerPoint), Google Workspace (Gmail, Calendar, Drive, Docs, Sheets), Dropbox, Trello, Miro, Evernote

Digital Marketing WordPress, SquareSpace, Adobe Photoshop, Meta Business Suite (Instagram & Facebook Pages, Ads, Insights), Instagram (Posts, Reels, Stories), and email marketing platforms including Mailchimp, Vertical Response, and Constant Contact

EDUCATION

PER SCHOLAS, Software Engineer Boot Camp

2023

NONPROFIT TECH FOR GOOD (NTFG), Certificate (Digital Marketing & Fundraising)

2020

YALE UNIVERSITY, Master of Arts in Religion

NORTHWESTERN COLLEGE, Bachelor of Arts in English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CHIEF OPERATING OFFICER, Metropolitan Pavilion 2003 to 2021 (Director of Marketing, 2001 to 2003)

Presided over general management & administration for a premier New York City special events venue and onsite-events production company serving an array of commercial and nonprofit clients, including Google, New York University, Samsung, the Affordable Art Fair, and PULSE Art Fair. As a direct report to the President/Owner, I consistently demonstrated reliability, attention to detail, loyalty, and high regard for confidentiality.

- Developed and maintained comprehensive IT/network management and software packages for 50+ licensed users
- Oversaw all companywide internal communications to ensure clarity and consistency in management directives
- Coordinated leadership team (preparing meeting agenda, scheduling, driving intra-team communications)
- Directed Accounting and Administration Department, including HR, IT, compliance, government relations, community relations, legal, commercial insurance and more
- Built from scratch all standard operating procedures including administrative procedures, digital marketing, and human resources (employee onboarding, benefits enrollments, etc.), and recurring government licensing
- Grew revenue by 510% (from \$3.1 million to \$15.7 million; 32% annualized), 2003 to pandemic lockdown
- Increased repeat client rate from 50% to 67%
- Tracked digital marketing metrics and oversaw search engine optimization (SEO)
- Led competitive-set reporting to inform strategic marketing decisions
- Managed relationships with and served as liaison to local elected officials, government departments and agencies, including the NYPD, FDNY, State Liquor Authority (SLA) and Community Board
- Handled all city and state permitting including street activities, public assembly and retail liquor service

NON PROFIT EXPERIENCE

FOUNDER, Ulysses S. Grant Revealed (GrantRevealed.com), 2021 to present. Created and maintaining educational website and social media channels about the life & times of Ulysses S. Grant, commander of U.S. forces in the Civil War and 18th U.S. president. **TREASURER, Hell's Kitchen Foundation, Inc.**, 2015 to present. Established a foundation awarding grants to artists with demonstrated need in Hell's Kitchen. Oversaw the formation of its board of directors, legal frameworks, and marketing and communications operations. Designated 2017 Storygiver Presenter by the American Fundraising Professionals NYC Chapter (AFP-NYC)

MEMBERSHIPS

Saint George's Society of New York - charity aiding British and Commonwealth citizens in New York City, 2007—present

Grant Monument Association - nonprofit promoting the accomplishments of and raising repair-and-completion funds for the tomb of

Ulysses S. Grant, 2021—present

Live Events Coalition (LEC), NY/NJ Chapter, Government Affairs committee, 2020–2021